(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E06 -= Mikes.Madonna.Story =- Subripped by zerox
这棵植物一定是母的
She's definitely a Wendy.
显然是公的
He is clearly a Sam.
爸爸，我自己种的还不清楚吗？ 它是母的
Dad, I think I know my own plant. She's a Wendy.
凯罗，我念过医学
Carol, I went to medical school, okay?
我能找到答案
So, I think I can settle that.
是母的
That's a Wendy.
你俩在干什么？
What are you two doing?
我在做实验，我一直跟温蒂说话
Well, it's an experiment. I've been talking to Wendy here...
另外一棵没名字的不管
and giving what's-his-name the silent treatment.
最后看看谁长得快
And well see which one grows faster.
-优胜者会成为今晚的菜 -爸爸!
- And the winner becomes tonights salad. - Dad.
有个女的要找麦克
There's a girl here for Mike.
本，你就让人家站在门外？
Ben, did you just leave her standing outside?
她是个女的，我要怎样？
She's a girl, Mom. What do you want me to do?
让她进来？
Let her in?
看来你对女的没什么好感
Sounds like you have some pretty strong feelings about girls.
不，我只是不喜欢她们
No, I just don't like them.
本，有朋友来访.
Well, Ben, if a friend comes to the door...
你应该让别人进来
you should let them in.
-你好 -你好
- Why, hello. - Hi.
-麦克在吗？ -也许在
- Is Mike home? - Possibly.
很可能在，我去看看
Quite possibly. Let me check.
麦姬？
Maggie?
请进
Please, come in.
谢谢
Thanks.
随便坐
Would you like to have a seat?
我叫麦姬，麦克的母亲 这是杰森
I'm Maggie, Mike's mother. This is Jason.
-你好 -这是本和凯罗
- Hello. - Ben. Carol.
-你呢？ -我叫丽莎
- And you are? - Lisa.
我是麦克的朋友
I'm Mike's, like, friend.
原谅他，他不喜欢女孩子
You have to forgive him, he doesn't like girls.
其实我不把自己当作女孩子
Well, actually, l, like, don't consider myself a girl.
我是一个的女人
I consider myself a woman.
说得对
And rightly so, I'm sure.
我去叫麦克
I'll call Mike.
麦克
Mike.
不好意思，他不在家
I'm sorry, he doesn't seem to be here.
或许他也不喜欢女孩子
Guess he doesn't like girls, either.
走着瞧
Well see about that.
丽莎，吃点什么吗？
So, Lisa. Dip?
-不了 -不？
- No. - No.
丽莎.
Hey, Lisa...
真让人喜出望外
what a pleasant surprise.
我刚好经过，我要跟男朋友分手
I was just in the neighborhood, breaking up with my old boyfriend.
-是吗？ -是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
他太幼稚了
He was just too immature.
-他岁数比你小？ -不，他27岁
- Was he younger than you? - No, he was 27.
真巧.
What an amazing coincidence...
我刚打电话跟女朋友分手
cause I was just up on the phone, breaking up with my old girlfriend.
她43岁
She was 43.
是啊，以狗的年龄来算
Yeah, in dog years maybe.
你们也很久没探望史蒂夫伯伯了
You guys haven't seen Uncle Steve in a while.
就去看望一下他吧
Why don't you go take a walk by his place?
麦克，史蒂夫伯伯住在新疆
Mike, your uncle Steve's in Connecticut.
那怎样了？
So?
而且他去世了
And he's dead.
你们去吃点什么吗？
Should you guys go have a snack?
好吧，咱们走
Right, okay. All right, come on, guys.
-丽莎，幸会 -幸会
- Lisa, very nice to meet you. - You, too.
麦姬，再见
See you, Maggie.
直呼你的名字没关系吧？
You don't mind if I call you Maggie, do you?
没关系
No.
爸爸，那女孩穿得真是的
God, Dad, do you believe the top that girl was wearing?
我没注意到
I didn't notice.
拜托，差不多等于没穿上衣
Come on, Dad, she might as well have had no shirt on at all.
权衡轻重.
Well, all things considered...
幸好她还没到那种地步
I'm glad she didn't choose to go that route.
我同意
Me, too.
凯罗，带本出去玩吧
Carol, why don't you take Ben and go outside.
-为什么？ -因为我要跟爸爸谈谈
- Why? - Because I need to talk to your father.
关于麦克滥交朋友？
About Mikes friend with the major-league yabos?
你们俩出去
Out! Both of you.
出去干什么呢？
What are we supposed to do outside?
随便，跟草地说话吧
I don't care. Talk to the lawn.
或者剪剪草
No. it needs mowing as it is.
那女孩穿得真是的!
Did you see the top that girl was wearing?
杰森，她是个婊子
Jason, she's a tramp.
不是吧
Come on, Maggie.
我承认她确实穿得.
No. I mean, I admit she doesn't dress with a lot of....
她是没穿
Clothing.
没有品味
Taste.
但我们还不了解她
But we don't know anything about the girl.
她跟27岁的人交往
Jason, she was going out with a 27-year-old.
这样就成婊子了？
And that makes her a tramp?
也许他们是志同道合
Well, maybe they shared the same interests.
那正是婊子的行为
That makes her a tramp.
麦姬.
Oh, Maggie.
杰森，她连笑起来.
Jason, she doesn't even giggle...
也不像一个15岁的女孩子
the way a 15-year-old is supposed to giggle.
好，我去通知国防部
Well, I'll call the National Guard.
你也懂我意思
You know what I mean.
当一个15岁的女孩上门找我儿子时.
When a 15-year-old girl comes to my door, asking for my son...
她应该感到局促不安
she should feel awkward and uncomfortable.
但这次是我感到局促不安
With this girl, I feel awkward and uncomfortable.
瞧，她笑了
See, she giggles.
我刚说错了
My mistake.
你们能不能出去一下？
So, do you think you guys could leave?
-为什么？ -好让我们和果汁
- Why? - So we can have some juice.
我们在屋里就不能喝？
You mean, you can't have juice with us in the room?
你们买下9个房间的屋子.
Fine, fine. But I don't know why you guys bought a house with nine rooms...
怎么都不使用呢？
if you're not gonna use them.
说得够婉转
Subtle, Mike.
就这样，我对埃德说分手 他，他哭了
So anyway, when I told Ed I was breaking up with him, he, like, cried.
-可怜虫 -确实是
- it was so pathetic. - Yeah, that is pathetic.
我从来不哭
l, like, never cry.
真的？
Really?
除了那次被车碾到脚
Well, once when a car rode over my foot, I winced.
麦克，你真帅
You're, like, so cute, Mike.
怎么说呢？
Hey, what can I say?
帅就是一个字
Yeah, I'm cute. I'm damn cute.
埃德也太多心了
Plus, Ed was like super possessive.
我只是跟菲尔去露营，他就生气了
I mean, he, like, got upset because I went camping with Phil Crawly...
-基本上只是朋友关系 -基本上？
- who's, like, just a friend, basically. - Basically?
-妈妈 -对不起
- Mom. - I'm sorry.
丽莎.
Lisa...
你跟27岁的人交往，父母怎么看？
so how did your parents feel about you going out with a 27-year-old?
-我妈妈很不满意 -是吗？
- Like, my mother, she was bummed. - Really?
也许她想跟他交往
Like, I think she wanted to go out with him.
那你父母离婚了？
I take it your parents are no longer together then?
-为什么？ -没什么，算了
- What makes you say that? - Nothing. Never mind.
好，麦克，今晚有节目吗？
So, like anyway, Mike, you wanna do something tonight?
刚才我刚分手了
Well, I did just end a very special relationship.
我也跟她胡混够了
But I think I've moped around about that long enough.
别忘了我和你爸 今晚要和库斯曼家出去.
Mike, don't forget that your father and I are going out...
你要负责照顾本和凯罗
with the Koosmans tonight, and you have to baby-sit Ben and Carol.
找个保姆行吗？
Can't we get a sitter?
这么急去哪里找？
On this short notice, not one without an axe.
本和凯罗逃命的功夫其实很好
So? Ben and Carol are quick on their feet.
-麦克 -好吧
- Mike? - Okay, okay.
或者今晚我过来这里吧
Hey, Mike, maybe I could, like, come over here tonight.
那样.
Yeah! That'd be--
丽莎这个周末就太枯燥了
Probably a very boring way for Lisa to spend a Saturday night.
不枯燥，我喜欢当保姆
No, it wouldn't be boring, Maggie. I just love baby-sitting.
这个女人真好
What a woman, huh, Mom?
确实
You betcha.
你是世界上最坏的植物
You are the ugliest plant alive.
凯罗悄悄对我说她讨厌你
Carol told me privately that she hates you.
-本，你在干什么？ -没什么
- Ben, what are you doing? - Nothing, Mom.
-好了吗？ -好了
- Okay, all set? - Yeah.
-跟他谈话了？ -对
- So? Did you talk to him? - Yeah.
他怎么说了？
Well, what did you say?
跟我们说的差不多
Well, pretty much what you and I discussed.
具体怎么说？
Like what, specifically?
就是那种父子谈话
Well, you know, it was one of those father-son talks.
原谅我，我没体验过那种谈话
Forgive me, Jason. I have never had one of those father-son talks.
-你怎么说？ -我问他.
- What did you say? - Well, that's where I say:
还好吗？“ 他回答：”很好
"How you doing, Son? " He says, "Pretty good, Dad."
我问：“你头上喷了定型喷雾..”
I say, "Is that mousse in your hair, or is it wet--"
杰森，说重点
Jason, get to the good part.
我告诉他大体上.
Honey, I just told him that in general...
关系应该慢慢地培养
I think that it's better to start slowly with a relationship...
要了解那个人，还要.
to get to know somebody, to get a--
-验艾滋病 -对，那个也要
- A medical report. - That, too, I guess.
那么.
So....
他们今晚打算怎样？
Well, what do you think they'll do tonight?
很可能看电视吧
Well, they'll probably watch TV.
如果他们不看电视呢？
Jason, what if they don't watch TV?
才15岁，15岁的男女会看电视？
I mean, he's only 15. He's too young to not watch TV.
若是15岁的少男少女不想看电视.
Well, if two teenage kids want to get together and not watch TV...
他们总会想到办法做别的事情
they're gonna find a way to do it.
我累了，今晚不出去了
I'm tired. Let's stay home.
-麦姬 -我要看电视
- Maggie. - I wanna watch The Love Boat.
鲍勃和艾伦3分钟后就来接我们了
Bob and Ellen are picking us up in three minutes.
我们真的不该留下？
Are you sure we shouldn't stay home?
你得明白，不管我们走到哪里.
You know, what you have to remember is that no matter where we are...
麦克脑里都会有把声音.
there's always that little voice inside Mike's head...
“麦克，我是你妈妈..”
saying, "Mike, this is your mother speaking."
麦克会诧异“妈，你找我干什么？”
And that's when Mike says, "Ma, what are you doing here? "
那把声音回答“我要提醒你..”
And the little voice says, "l just want to remind you that I love you...
“我一直都会很疼爱你”
"and I'll always love you...
“即使你和那女孩胡来”
"even if you break my heart by touching that girl somewhere."
你是指我让他产生愧疚感.
Okay, okay. So you're saying I've already saddled him with enough guilt...
一辈子摆脱不了？
to cripple him for life?
不，我是指他知道我们的价值观
No. I'm saying that he knows our values...
他知道我们疼爱他
and he knows that we care about him.
面对人生的重大抉择时.
And I know that he will consider that...
他会慎重考虑
anytime he makes one of life's big decisions.
希望你说得对
I hope you're right.
杰森，还是别去了
Jason, we are not leaving this house.
麦姬，库斯曼一家来了，走吧
Maggie, the Koosmans are here. Lets just go.
管他的库斯曼
To hell with the Koosmans.
快上车!
Come on, guys, lets go!
难道过去告诉鲍勃和艾伦.
Do you want to go out there and tell Bob and Ellen...
有女孩子来了，所以不能离开家？
that we can't leave our house because there's a girl in it?
不行吗？
Why not?
若是一个男孩和凯罗在家.
Would you leave Carol in there with a boy...
而那个男孩不穿衣服呢？
who looks like he just fell off an X-rated wedding cake?
你这是双重标准
This is a double standard.
人生就是这样，麦姬，走吧
Nobody said life was fair, Maggie. Lets go.
我了解你的心情
Honey, I know what you're feeling...
但我们不能替麦克做决定
but we should not try to make this decision for Mike.
不管怎样，他都要自己去处理
And no matter what happens, he's gonna live through it.
这样说就够了？
That's comforting.
她终于肯动了，他可以瞑目了
Hey, I saw her walk up. At least hell die happy.
该死的库斯曼
I hate the Koosmans.
抱紧我
Hold me.
这一刻.
Do you know how long I've waited for this?
我等了很久了
For the opportunity to do this?
这真是个大好的时机 我们可以为所欲为.
This is an incredible opportunity for me to do what I've always--
闭嘴，抱紧我
Shut up and hold me.
天哪，摸你哪里好呢？
Oh, my God. You have so many places to hold.
随便挑一个吧
Just pick one.
这电影真无聊
This movie happens to be very dull.
麦克不会有事的
Maggie, Mikes gonna be just fine.
没有情节，没有演技.
There's no story, no character...
纯粹是靠色情来争取票房
just a lot of gratuitous sex thrown in to boost ticket sales!
快坐下，我们知道了
We know. Sit down.
若是我们坐视不理 戏院老板又怎会知道.
How are theater owners going to know how we feel about this garbage...
-我们对这种垃圾电影的看法 -你现在是“站”视不理
- if we just sit through it? - Or stand through it, in your case.
对不对？
Oh, can it, will you?
麦姬，我们就看电影吧
Maggie, lets just watch the movie, okay?
你这种人应该留在家看
People like you should stay home and watch The Love Boat.
这是客厅，总算参观完我们家了
Well, this is the guest room. That about wraps up the tour of the house.
咱到楼下看电视吧
Lets go back downstairs, and we can watch TV or something.
-留在这吧，这里很好 -这里
- Stay here. It's, like, nice. - Here?
留在这干什么？楼下的电视更加.
What would we do in here? I mean, the TV downstairs is much more....
你这是要干什么？
Any idea what you're doing to me?
我要让我的嘴唇.
Well, you know, I was just trying to make my top lip match up, roughly...
-兴你的.. -我是说心里的想法
- with your-- - I mean, inside.
心里？
Inside?
这个.
Well, you know, its....
人的心理是最难捉摸的了
I find it's always so hard to say what someone else feels inside...
我爸是个精神病医师，他说.
and my dad, who is a psychiatrist, he says that...
两个人的想法.
no two people necessarily...
不一定要完全一致
have to feel the exact same inside.
-还有.. -我感到饥渴难耐
- And-- - I feel all steamy and tingly.
他没谈过“饥渴难耐”的事情
I don't specifically remember him mentioning "steamy and tingly."
我得问问他
I have to ask him about them.
上星期五的社会科测验怎样了？
So, how about that social studies test last Friday?
麦克，我有个怪念头
You know, Mike, I just got, like, a funny idea.
现在不怪吗？
Funny? Funnier than this?
我突然想到的
No. I mean, it just occurred to me.
你是..处男？
This gonna be the first time you've, like, ever done it?
丽莎，丽莎.
Lisa, Lisa, Lisa, Lisa.
不，对不起，太有意思了
No, I'm sorry. That's just so rich.
我不是个处男，在下不是
No, I'm not a virgin, Lisa. No, not this cowboy.
这就好了，信不信由你.
That's a relief. "Cause, like, believe it or not...
有些人到我们这种年纪还没做过呢
there are guys out there our own age who've never done it.
是啊，不受欢迎或者书呆子
Yeah. Rejects and nerds.
真的？那么.
Really? So....
刚才说到哪里了？
Where we're we?
我不太确定
I'm not sure.
我想起来了
Now I remember.
-是你 -没有
- Did. - Did not.
- Did, too. - Did not.
-我知道是你干的 -没有
- I know you did something to her. - Did not.
本，承认你杀死温蒂吧
Ben, why don't you just admit you killed Wendy?
然后我就杀死你，这样到头来.
And then I'll kill you, and we'll both feel a lot better...
-大家都舒服点 -不行
- about the whole thing. - No.
你明知自己是杀人凶手!
You're a killer and you know it!
-等等 -我不是!
- Hey, wait. Hold it. - Am not!
你们退到一边
Both of you, neutral corners.
爸爸
Dad...
我谈话的那颗植物死了
the plant I was talking to is dead.
这可不是个好兆头
Well, that does not bode well for the rest of the family, does it?
本杀死了温蒂
Dad! Ben killed Wendy.
我没有，胡说
I did not. Stop saying that.
本，你姐姐是不会搬弄是非的
Now, Ben, your sisters not one to make these things up.
你现在看着我，告诉我她搞错了
You look me squarely in the eye, and you tell me that she's mistaken...
这事就不提了
and then not another word will be said about it. Okay?
本？
Ben?
-温蒂是不是你杀的？ -不是
- Did you kill Wendy? - No.
好吧
Okay.
不完全是
Not exactly.
我说了一句坏话，叶子掉了一片 但我有救她
I said a mean thing to her, and a leaf fell off, but I tried to save her.
我真的有救她
I swear I tried to save her.
你怎么救她？
How exactly did you try to save her, Ben?
怎么救？当然是施肥了
How do you think? With the plant stuff.
天哪
Oh, my God.
本，整桶都倒进去了？
Ben, did you put the whole bottle on my plant?
我不是说我有救她吗？
See, I told you I tried to save her.
“1瓶盖肥料..”
"Mix one capful of Mighty Plant...
“需要混合8加仑水”
"with eight gallons of water."
什么意思？
What does that mean?
在温室的话5比8
Five-to-ten in the greenhouse.
孩子们，哥哥呢？
Kids, wheres your brother?
你是说“性欲狂”同志？
Oh, you mean Mr. Testosterone?
他在厨房
I think he's in the kitchen.
-麦克 -妈妈
- Hey, Mike. - Mom.
-丽莎呢？ -我怎么知道
- Wheres Lisa? - How should I know?
你们玩得开心吗？
Well, did you two have a good time together?
很开心
Sure.
-你们做什么了？ -我们一起玩了
- What'd you do? - We hung out.
看电视没有？
Did you watch any TV?
没有
No.
-你在看什么？ -冲浪杂志
- What's that you're reading? - Wind Surfer.
这期好看吗？
Good issue?
跟前面11期差不多
It's not much different from the last 11 issues.
有没有不舒服？
Are you feeling okay?
-没有 -很好
- Yeah, great. - Good.
-丽莎真是有意思 -是的
- So, Lisa seems like a very interesting girl. - Yeah.
-什么意思？ -什么什么意思？
- What does that mean? - What does what mean?
我说“她很有意思”.
I said, "She seems like an interesting girl"...
你说“是很有意思”，那是什么意思？
and you said, "Yeah." What does that mean?
我的意思是她很有意思
I don't know. I guess it means she's an interesting girl.
那么.
So...
你们俩下棋了？
did you guys play any board games?
什么也没干，好了吗？
Nothing happened, okay, Mom?
她要和我上床，我没有
She wanted to sleep with me, and I didn't do it.
我是同性恋，满意了吧？
I'm probably gay. Are you happy now?
-麦克 -什么？
- Mike. - What?
你绝对不是同性恋
I'm pretty sure you're not gay.
这还得看远一点
Yeah, I guess that was a long shot, huh?
麦克.
You know, Michael...
不和某人上床，这不是不正常
theres nothing wrong with choosing not to sleep with somebody.
你应该等待你爱的人
I mean, you can even wait for someone you love.
人们都是这样的
People do it all the time.
算了吧，我这样做并不是高尚.
Come on, Mom. It's not like I did some big noble thing here.
只是软弱无能
I just wimped out.
好吧，软弱无能
Okay, so you wimped out.
仔细想想，你放弃了什么？
But think about it for a minute. What did you really wimp out of?
换一种说法.
Let me rephrase that.
你在乎丽莎吗？
Do you care about Lisa?
你在乎她的感受.
I mean, do you care about what she feels or thinks...
在乎她的喜怒哀乐？
or if she's happy or sad?
关心她的遭遇吗？
Do you really care what happens to her?
至少不想看到她被车撞到
Well, I wouldn't want to see her get hit by a truck.
她有没有在乎你？
And do you think she cares about you?
对，她和我一样
Yeah, in the same kind of way.
你放弃的是没有跟她分享很珍贵的东西
So you wimped out of sharing something very special with someone who....
那你愿、意跟谁分享？ 也不想那个人被车撞吧？
Well, whose face you wouldn't want to see on the grille of an 18-wheeler?
我懂你意思了
Yeah. I guess I see what you mean.
不过丽莎.
But, Lisa....
她有种很特别的.
There was something about her, Mom. She's got....
阿飞？
Major-league yabos?
总的来说是的
Well, in a nutshell, yeah.
丽莎长得很漂亮
Lisa is a great-looking girl, Mike.
但漂亮的女孩多的是
But there are other great-looking girls out there...
其中有些很热情，很关心别人
who also happen to be warm, caring people.
是吗？
Really?
你一定会找到的
And you're gonna find one.
遇见合适的人，在合适的时间
And when the right girl and the right time comes along...
你就不会再感到软弱了
I think you'll be feeling anything but wimpy.
也许你说得对
Yeah, maybe you're right.
你可能被吓着了
You'll be a little scared at first...
但相信我，这是可以克服的
but trust me, you'll find a way to overcome it.
你爸爸就是
Your father did.
爸爸？
Dad?
他终于等到了合适的人
So I guess you're saying that he waited for the right girl.
你可以这么说
Yeah, I guess you could say that.
我见过她，她人很好
I met her. She was very nice.
嘿
Hey.
-没事吧？ -我很好
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm fine, Dad.
真的
Really.
晚安，麦克
Okay, Mike. Sleep tight, huh?
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 03.12.2006